Guide to the Walter Langford Smith Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Walter Langford Smith papers
1901-1911
MS 1126
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
Correspondence, financial papers, photographs, and memorabilia chiefly relating to Smith's term as a special student at the Yale Law School (1905-1906). Also included are sixteen letters (1904-1906) written to him by his father.
Smith, Walter Langford, 1885-1952
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Warren H. Smith, 1952.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Walter Langford Smith was born on April 12, 1885, in Rochester, New York. His mother, Helena Laura Denton, was the daughter of a deaf-mute who had inherited a large fortune. As his mother died when Walter was five, Walter inherited this fortune when he came of age. In 1905, Smith entered Yale Law School as a special student, but dropped out after inheriting his fortune in 1906. He spent the rest of his life in Rochester, New York, traveling to Europe and American resorts and driving sports cars. He died in Rochester, on August 6, 1952.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, financial papers, photographs, and memorabilia chiefly relating to Smith's term as a special student at the Yale Law School (1905-1906). Also included are sixteen letters (1904-1906) written to him by his father.
Fathers and sons; Law; Smith, Walter Langford, 1885-1952; Smith, William Henry, 1850-1922; Yale Law School; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, financial papers, photographs, and memorabilia make up the papers of Walter Langford Smith, a special student at the Yale Law School in 1905 and 1906. Included are sixteen letters from his father William Henry Smith (1850-1922), and several letters from friends, sixteen photographs of unidentified people, cards, receipts, and similar materials.
  - Correspondence
    - William Henry Smith, 1904-1906 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)
    - Walter Langford Smith
      - Outgoing, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Incoming, 1901-1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bills and receipts, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: unidentified people in Paris, Florida, and other places, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Postcards, one decorated with feathers, 1906, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Memorabilia
    - Yale Cooperative Society membership card, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Cigarette card, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Theater ticket stubs, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Advertising card for the Chorus Girls' Masque Ball after a Yale-Columbia football game, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Receipt, baggage checks, and envelope for a train trip to Rochester, New York, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)